（東条）あいつに伝えときな。
楽しかったぜってな。
Now, you there... Tell
him this: "It was fun."
（男鹿）ぷはっ！
The Doctor Has Arrived
（犬の遠吠え）
（美咲）((いい？ちゃんと探して
連れてくるまで→
Listen up! Until you bring them back,
I'm not letting you into the house!
家には　入れないからね！))
ふ～っ…。
（ドアの開閉音）
ただいま～。
I'm home.
（ヒルダ）遅い！
うっ！…ああ？
You're late!
（ヒルダ）まったく　今までどこを
ほっつき歩いておった。→
Where in blazes have you been
tramping about all this time?
私は　坊っちゃまのため
四方走り回っていたというのに→
While I traversed the four corners
of the world in service to my master!
貴様は　楽しくケンカごっこか？
Were you having fun playing "beat 'em up"?
お　おい…。
あげく　よその男の背に坊っちゃま
を預けたまま帰ってくるとは→
Hey!
To think you would slink home after leaving
the master stuck on that man's back...
何たる体たらく！
You're pathetic!
ま　まてよ！何で　お前が…→
W-Wait, how do you...
ていうか
もう俺　親じゃねえんだろ。
Anyway, I'm not his parent anymore, right?
愚か者！
うっ！
Fool!
今　この現在　貴様以外に
坊っちゃまの親がどこにいる。
何！？
Answer me: Who other than you would
be the master's parent at the moment?
（ラフマニノフ）ムー。
（ムームー）マー。
What?
ん？…え？
坊っちゃまの症状は
私には判断つかんのでな。
As I could not determine
the master's illness,
やはり専門の者を連れて来る事に
したのだ。
I decided I had to bring
back a specialist with me.
粗相のないように気をつけろ。
Watch your manners.
魔界でも高名な医者だ。
ムー。
This is a well-known doctor
in the Demon World.
《医者？こいつが？》
Doctor?
This guy?
《レベル１で
余裕で倒せそうだろ》
He looks easy for a level-1
character to beat.
（ラミア）何をしている！
早く入りなさい！
What are you doing?
Hurry and get in here!
（ラミア）まったく　こんな狭い所で
ベルゼ様を育てていたのね。
Sheesh... I can't believe that Beelze-sama
is being raised in this cramped little house.
あきれちゃった。
I'm flabbergasted.
えっ？誰！？
Who?
おいおいおいおい！
医者ってまさか→
Wait, wait, wait...
Don't tell me... this
little brat is the doctor?
このガキの事かよ！えらい
ちっせえぞ。小４ってとこか。
Dang, you're tiny... What
are you, a 4th grader?
つ～か　こいつも悪魔？
迷子の子とかじゃねえの？
And wait, she's a Demon too?
She's not just some lost little girl?
無礼者！！
Insolence!
ふ～ん　なるほどね。
あんたが男鹿？
Ah, I see.
You're Oga? Just as useless
a man as I've heard...
噂ど～り使えなさそうな男。
きいた…東条より重い一撃…。
That hurt worse than Tojo's...
てめえ！
いきなり　何てことしやがる！！
Why, you...! What the hell was that for?
おまけに貧乏くさい。一緒に
暮らしてるヒルダ姉様がかわいそう。
And you stink of poverty!
I feel sorry for Miss Hilda
having to live with you.
あと　なんか生臭い！
まあ　そう言うな　ラミア。
生臭いのは　川に落ちたからだ。
And you smell like a swamp!
About that last part, Lamia, he smells
like that because he fell in the river.
そこしか否定しねえのかよ！
てめえ　このガキ！ちょっと来い！！
That's the only part you correct?!
You little brat!
Get over here!
大体　大魔王様も　大魔王様よ。
このっ！この　この！
And really, the Great Demon
Lord never changes either!
Why, you...
人間なんかに魔王の親が…。
No human is fit to be
parent of a Demon Lord...
この～っ！
務まるわけないじゃない。
遅い遅い！医者の立場から
言わせてもらえばね…。
くっそ～っ！！
Too slow, too slow!
Speaking from my position as a doctor...
今回の事は　目に見えていた事
なのよ…ああっ！
少し黙れ。
I'm starting to see what's wrong here!
Be quiet for a bit.
はっ　はっ…。
コホン　改めて紹介しよう。
宮廷薬師フォルカス・ラフマニノフ先生と→
Let me introduce everyone again.
This is the Court Physician Doctor Furcas
Rachmaninoff and his assistant, Lamia.
その助手　ラミアだ。
よっ。
Hi.
《やっぱ　こっちが医者か…
ったく→
So that thing was the doctor!
Sheesh, be more obvious about it!
てめえも　まぎらわしいんだよ
ボケが。最初に喋れや》
Say something first!
《つ～か　このキャラもどうなの？
ね～だろ　デザイン的に→
And anyway, what's with this character?
This design has got to go.
テキトーかよ》
It's totally winged!
（ラフマニノフ）テキトーじゃないっ！
うおっ！
I am not winged!
《しかも　心　読みやがる》
And it can read my mind!
読んでないっ！
ううっ！
I am not reading it!
いいか　最初に一つだけ
言っておくぞ。
Okay? Let me say this first.
私は　本当は
めちゃくちゃカッコイイぞ。
I am actually extremely cool.
師匠は極度の人間嫌いでね。
ムームーの姿を使ってきているのよ。
Doctor has an extreme hatred of humans, see.
So he uses a Mu-mu body instead.
あ　これムームーね。
（ムームー）マー。
Oh, this is a Mu-mu.
というわけで　駆けつけてみれば
患者がいないとは　これいかに？
Now then, I've come rushing here,
but I don't see the patient?
うっ…知らね～よ。朝起きたら
もういなかったんだし。
How should I know? He was gone
when I woke up this morning.
まあ　ヒルダ殿のお話で
おおよその見当はついてるがね。
Well, after listening to Hilda-dono, I
believe I have a grasp of the situation.
ベルゼ様の症状は王熱病。→
Beelze-sama's illness is Royal Fever.
王族など　潜在能力の高い者ほど
かかりやすい→
It is common for royalty with large
amounts of latent power to succumb to it.
知恵熱のようなものだな。
Sort of like a teething fever.
知恵熱？
Teething fever?
うむ。幼児が成長する際に起こす
発熱だ。→
Yes. It is a fever which
occurs when a baby grows.
ベルゼ様の場合　すでに何度か
経験されておられるのだろう。→
I'm sure you've experienced it with
Beelze-sama a number of times by now, yes?
それでヒルダ殿も
油断したのだろうが…→
Perhaps that is why Hilda-dono
was caught off guard...
今回は　少しばかり事情が違う。→
But this time the situation
is a little different.
なんせ　ここは人間界だ。→
Why? Because this is the Human World.
ベルゼ様の魔力を発散させるには
人間の手助けが必要となる…。→
Human assistance is required for
Beelze-sama to unleash his magical power.
ところが　成長したベルゼ様の
魔力は　君には大きすぎた。→
Therefore, Beelze-sama's growing magical
power has become too great for you to handle.
あまりに膨大な魔力が
流れ込もうとしたため→
In order to prevent a such a great
magic force from flowing out into you,
ベルゼ様は無意識に　君との
リンクを切ってしまったのだ。→
Beelze-sama subconsciously
cut the link between you.
そうしなければ
君を殺しかねないからね。
For if he did not, he would
have surely killed you.
つまり！あんたがベルゼ様の
成長に追いついていないのが→
In other words, this is all your fault for not
growing fast enough to keep up with Beelze-sama!
全ての原因よ！わかったか　ボケ！！
わっ！！
Get the picture, half-wit?!
少し黙れ。
Stay silent for a little longer.
で　ベル坊は新しい親を求めて
東条の方に行ったってわけか…。
So Baby Beel went looking for
a new parent and found Tojo...
いや　それはない。もし　あの男が
親となりうるなら…→
No, that's not the case.
If that man has what it takes
to be the master's parent,
すでに坊っちゃまは　魔力を解放し
熱も下がってしかるべきだ。
the master would have already
released his magical power,
and his fever should have gone down.
何よりも　あの男
悪意というものが感じられん。
And besides... I could not
sense any malice from that man.
強さだけなら
申し分ないのだが…。
I have no complaints about
his strength, however.
見てたのかよ。
おそらく資質の問題なのだろうな。
You were watching?
It's probably a temperament issue.
《まてよ…じゃあ…
ありゃあ　何だったんだ？》
Wait... Then...
What was that?
しかし　そうなると確かに…→
But it is true...
何故　坊っちゃまは
あの男にくっついているのか…。
Why is the master sticking to that man?
（ベル坊）ダーブー。
やれやれ　今日も蒸し暑いなあ。
Man, it's damn hot today too.
（祭りばやし）
（東条）ん～っ…チチチチッ…。
ニャ～オ～。
ほ～ら　おいで　おいで。怖くないよぉ。
Here kitty kitty, no need to be afwaid...
（東条）おっ　よしよし　来たのか…。
ニャッ！
Yes-yes, come here...
（庄次）何やってんすか　東条さん。
ニャーッ！！
What are you doing, Tojo-san?
さっさと運んじまいましょうよ～。あんたのバイトでしょ？
Hurry and carry these boxes!
It's your job, remember?
ったく　急に呼び出されたと
思ったら　祭りの後片付けっすか？
Man... You call me all of a sudden, and it's
to help you clean up after the festival?
俺は便利屋じゃね～んすよ。
I'm not your little helper boy, you know.
庄次…てめえ　歯食いしばれ！
（庄次）何でっ！？
Shoji...
You're gonna get it!
Wait!
（庄次）やれやれ　すっかり
遅くなっちまいましたね。
Man... It's really gotten late.
動物の気配がする…犬か？猫か？
I can sense an animal.
A dog? A cat?
この人は…。
This guy...
（カラン…）
そこかっ！？
おっ！
There!
ダーブー。
あ　赤ん坊っすね。
It's a baby...
おいおい　ヤバイんじゃないっすかこれ。
Hey, this ain't good, man...
まさか　捨て子とかいうんじゃ…
って！
Don't tell me that it's been abandoned...
ちちちちっ…よしよしよし
おいで　おいで～。
Come 'ere, come 'ere! That's a good boy...
ダーブー。
（庄次）ちょっと～　動物扱い？→
Wait, you're treating him like an animal?
あんた　犬猫じゃないんだから。
You're not a dog or a cat!
よしよし　おいで　おいで～。
Yes, that's right... Come up 'ere...
ダーブー。
キッ！
ういっ！
How cute!
な　なついた！？
H-He likes him!
庄次…俺　こいつ飼う！
Shoji...
I'm keeping him!
い～っ！？→
いやいやいや　飼うとかじゃ
ないですから　それ！
No-no-no... You don't "keep" some baby!
（東条）絶対飼う！
（庄次）おかしいっす　東条さん！
I'm totally keeping him!
This isn't right, Tojo-san!
とにかくだ　坊っちゃまを
助けるには　まず何より→
Anyway, the most important thing is
to improve your growth as his parent.
貴様の親としての成長が
必要となる。
うっ…。
今回に限り　私は全面的に
貴様の味方だ。
This time only, I am 100%
on your side, you bastard.
男なら　しっかりと勝って
坊っちゃまを取り戻せ！
If you're a man, then suck it up
and win! Take the master back!
魔王の親ともあろうものが
負けたまま泣き寝入りは許さんぞ。
Those who seek to be the Demon Lord's parent
will not be forgiven for crying
themselves to sleep after losing!
あ？
何　勝手に決めてんだ　コラ…。
What the hell are you deciding for me?
まだ負けてね～よ。
勝負の途中だ　ボケ！
I ain't lost yet.
The fight's still on, idiot.
それでよい。
That'll do.
（ラミア）
話は　まとまったようですね。
うむ。
It seems like we've come to an understanding.
Yes.
では…始めましょうか。
Then, shall we start?
It seems like we've come to an understanding.
（ラミア）話は　まとまったよ～ですね。
うむ…。
Yes.
あ？
（ラミア）では…。
Then, shall we start?
始めましょうか…イヒ。
んっ？
Yes. Now shoot him.
うむ。では　やってくれ。
はあっ！？
ちょっ…待て待て待て！
始めるって何を！？
Wait, wait... What's starting?
って　お前　何持ってんだ　それ！
おいっ！
And what the hell is that you're holding?
Hey!
Cut the  noise! Quiet!
うるさいっ！黙れ！
てめえ…。
Why, you...
Don't worry. Just a little shock therapy.
案ずるな　ただのショック療法だ。
坊っちゃまと貴様のリンクを
つなぎ直すためのな…。
This is to repair the link
between you and the master.
あぁ！？ふざけんなよ！
誰がベル坊を取り戻すっつった！？
Give me a break! When did I say I was
gonna get linked with Baby Beel again?
んなもん　ど～でもいいんだよ！
I don't give a crap about that!
オレはただ　東条の野郎を
ぶっとばしたいだけだ！
I just want to beat that jerk, Tojo!
I said to be quiet.
（ラミア）黙れっての…。
（銃声）
あ…。
（バタッ！）
I shot him with the spirit drug
made from Uroboros's bones...
（ラミア）ウロボロスの骨から作った
霊薬を撃ち込みました。
This is the best thing for the
growth of the Demon Lord's parent.
魔王の親を成長させるには
これが一番です。→
With this drug, he's been thrown into a
world that's a fixed loop within his mind.
薬によって　ループ状に
固定された精神世界。→
今　彼はその中にいます。
The only way to escape is to
restore the link with Beelze-sama.
そこから脱出するには
ベルゼ様とのリンクを→
修復するしかない…。
Yes. But one false step,
and he can never return.
（ラフマニノフ）うむ…一歩間違えば→
戻ってこられなくなる…
危険な賭けだ。
It is a dangerous gamble.
Never return? And that means...?
戻ってこられない…というと？
Right! He'll die!
はい　死にます！
W-Where is this place?
な…なんだ？ここ…。
The inside of your mind...
（古市）心の中だよ　お前のな…。
古市っ！…って　ムキムキ！？
Furuichi... And you're stacked!
オレは古市じゃない！
モンテスキューだ！
I am not Furuichi, I am Montesquieu!
はあっ！？
Three Branches of Government!
三権分立っ！！
がは～っ！！
どはっ！どはぁ～！！
Wait, wait... What the heck
kind of attack name is that?
ちょっ　待て待て！
なんだそりゃ　技名？
なんか　お前
今　ノリで殴っただろ！
You just hit me 'cause you
thought you could, right?
I did not hit you!
殴ってない！
You did too! Don't deny it!
殴っただろ！
そこを否定すんなよ！
いいか　よく聞け相棒。
今　お前さんは→
Listen well, dear friend.
You are currently in an
extremely dangerous situation.
とてつもなく危険な状態に
あるんだぜ。→
オナラで言うと　ちょっとしめった
スカシッぺってとこだ。
To put it in terms of farts, you've
let out sort of a juicy, silent one.
Why in terms of farts?
何故オナラ！？
ってか危険じゃね～し。
And that's not dangerous at all.
The Uroboros that girl shot you with
is a snake that eats its own tail.
（古市）
あの　おじょうちゃんが撃ち込んだウロボロスってのは→
自分の尾を飲み続ける
ヘビの事だ…わかるか？
Do you understand?
The world you are in now is the same way.
今　お前のいる　この世界も
同じ状態だ。
To escape from here, you
must search for the key.
ここから出たければ
鍵を探す事だ。
鍵！？
そう。
Key?
Yes. Search for the thing you need most.
お前が一番
必要としている者を探せ。
What's that supposed to mean? Explain
it in a way I can understand!
なんだよ　それ。もうちょっと
ちゃんと説明しろよ！
In other words...
つまり…あっ　時間だ！
Oops, time's up.
In other words what?!
つまりなんだ～！？お～い！
Hey!
What the hell...
《なんだこれ…
なんだこれ…え～っと→
What the hell...
Um... So basically, um...
要するに…何だ…あの
ラミアとかいうガキに撃たれて→
I was shot by that Lamia girl, and
now I'm in some kind of deep sleep?
オレは今　昏睡状態ってことか？→
Then all this is inside of my head?
ってことは
これ全部　オレの頭ん中！？→
What the hell am I thinking?
何考えてんだ　オレ…》
（姫川花・神崎花）
ヒヒヒヒ…エヘヘへ…。
うっ！？
Hello, lovely lady!
やあ　すてきなおじょうさん。
お散歩かい？ウフフ。
Going for a walk?
ひっ　姫川と神崎！？
Himekawa and Kanzaki!
Yes, it will be a brilliant gold...
♪～　そう　ぼくらはすてきな
黄金色の
...afternoon, and we can't wait!
♪～　午後を楽しんでるのさぁ
It can't be... You guys are my...
ま　まさか　お前らがオレの…。
（姫川花）♪～　黄金色の風に乗って
いや！な　わけね～な。
（神崎花）♪～　ふらぃあうえ～い
No, that can't be.
ない。うん　ないない！
（姫川花）♪～　ふぁ～らうえ～い
Nope. Not a chance.
《お　落ち着け　オレ…》
C-Calm down...
（ガシャーン）
《あ？》
That's...
《こいつらは…！？》
（汽笛）
は～はははっ
お前なぞには追いつけまい。
（汽笛）
One such as you cannot overtake me!
（邦枝）ば　ばっかじゃないの！
A-Are you an idiot?
え～～っ！？
（汽笛）
お？
Can you even follow me to
Lord Haptom Oggah's heart?
ハップトム・オッガ卿の
ハートまで辿りつけるかな！？
ば　ばっかじゃないの！
A-Are you an idiot?!
むっはははは！
（邦枝）ばっかじゃないの～！
うわあ～っ！！
Are you an idiot?!
（アランドロン羊）めえぇぇ～めえ？
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
めえぇ～めええ～。
うわあ！はあ　はあ…
うわ～っ！！
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
W-Wait a second...
ちょっ　ちょっと待てよ…。
Furuichi showed up, then
Kanzaki and Himekawa...
古市　出て来て…
で　神崎と姫川で…→
Then there was Hilda and
Kunieda and Alaindelon...
次がヒルダと邦枝
アランドロンだろ…→
Which means, if it follows the pattern...
ってことは
パターンから行くと…。
あっ　ん！？
やっぱり…オレか！
I knew it... Me!
（ホワイト男鹿）イエス　イッツミー！
Yup. Called it.
だよな…だよなぁ…。
大体この手のは
最期に自分自身を→
This is totally the pattern where I end
up having to defeat myself in the end.
倒して終わりって
パターンだよな…。
No!
（ホワイト男鹿）いや…。
へ？
I don't like violence.
暴力はよくない…。
あ？
Nothing comes from violence.
暴力からは何も生まれない。
人には話し合う力がある。
People have the power to talk things out.
Using words instead of fists to bridge one's
differences is the first step to world peace!
拳ではなく
言葉を用いての対話こそが→
世界平和への第一歩！
え～っと　じゃあ　どうするわけ？
Um, then what should I do?
決まっているだろう。今から
じっくりと話し合いをする。
Isn't it obvious?
We shall have a long conversation together.
お互いの思う所を
忌憚なく述べ合い→
Both laying our feelings bare to each other,
we shall have a lively exchange of ideas.
活発な意見交換を交わし
双方の折衝点が見つかるまで→
We take our time finding each
other's negotiating points,
時間をかけて
ひとつずつの懸念を…。
and one by one our doubts...
めんどくせえ…お？
Sounds like a pain.
左の頬を殴られたら…
右の頬もお願いしま～す。
Since my left cheek was punched,
please do the right one now!
えぇっ…えい！
Since my right cheek was punched,
右の頬を殴られたら…。
えぇっ！
please do the left one now!
左の頬もお願いしま～す。
う　うるせぇ～！え～い！
Shut up!
左の頬を殴られたら…。
くっそ～！！
Since my left cheek was punched...
God damn it!
Please do the right one now!
右の頬もお願いしま～す。
（ホワイト男鹿）あははは　おほほほ…。
え～い！！
こんのぉ～！！
Why, you...
はぁ　はぁ…ん！？
Since my right cheek was punched,
右の頬を殴られたら…
左の頬もお願いしま～す。
please do the left one now!
くっ…う～ん！
おわ～っ！！
（ホワイト男鹿）あははは　おほほほ…。
えっ！？おわ～っとっと…。
うわ～っ！
ど　どけっ！どけぇ～！！
Move it!
くぅ…くそっ！
オ　オレは…オレは…！
Damn it... I... Why, you...
Baby Beel?
す～ぴ～　す～ぴ～。
ベル坊…。
Baby Beel...
うう…うっ！
It looks like he's found him.
（ラミア）
どうやら見つけたようですね…。
Yes, but the issue begins now.
うむ…だが問題は　ここからだ。
Right. The rejection has begun.
はい　拒絶が始まります。
くっ…うぐっ～！
うああああ～っ！！
Hey, Kaoru.
（東条）≪よお　かおる≫
Studying for entrance exams again today?
今日も受験勉強か？大変だな。
何だこりゃ…さっぱり　わからん。
Seems tough. What is this? I have no clue.
（陣野）虎…なんだ？
Tora.
What is it?
フン…付き合えよ。
Come with me.
I fought with Oga.
男鹿とやり合ったぜ。
珍しいな
お前が傷作ってくるなんて。
It's rare that someone injures you.
Yeah. He's got backbone,
just like we thought.
ああ…思った通り
骨のある野郎だったぜ。→
とりあえず　ぶっとばしといたが…
なぁに　あいつは　また来るぜ。
I may have bashed him
good, but he'll be back.
実はな　虎…
オレもお前に話があったんだ。
Actually, Tora, I have something
I need to mention to you.
ん？
（陣野）お前にくっついている
その赤ん坊の事だ。
It's about that baby that's sticking to you.
ああ…。
す～ぴ～。
Do you know the other name
for the Rampaging Ogre?
（陣野）
知ってるか？アバレオーガの
もうひとつの名前。→
The BoB Brawler.
子連れ番長という。
はあ！？
But lately it seems like his
Baby ain't on Board any more.
その男鹿が　最近
赤ん坊を連れてないらしい。
So, Tora... Is that Oga's...
なあ虎　そいつ男鹿の…。
That sounds like an interesting story.
（神崎）おもしろそうな話
してんじゃね～か。
（姫川）俺達も混ぜろよ　東条。
Let us join in the fun, Tojo.
ふん…。
す～ぴ～。
（チッ　チッ　チッ　チッ）
It has been 6 hours since
we injected the drug.
（ラフマニノフ）
薬を撃ち込んで６時間…。→
If, after waiting this
long, he doesn't wake up...
これだけ待って
目覚めぬということは…。
It failed? It didn't work?
（ラミア）失敗？失敗しちゃった！？
イエ～イ！
Yay!
う？あ…。
お…おはよう～。
G-Good morning!
（ラミア）きゃあああ～！！
はははは～っ！
つかまえたぞ　このガキ！
I caught you, you little brat!
I'll teach you some manners, I will!
てめ～には礼儀ってもんを
たっぷり教えてやる！
Let me go! Let me go, you perv!
はなせ！はなせ！このスケベ～！
ぬはははっ！何とでも言え！
（ラミア）やめて～！
Go ahead and yell!
It looks like you passed through the crisis.
どうやら峠を越えたようだな。
あ？
あとは坊っちゃまを
取り戻すだけだ…。
All that's left is to take the master back.
気分はどうだ？
はなせ～！うわぁ～！
How do you feel?
Let me go!
はん　いいわけね～だろ。
I feel awful. Whaddaya expect?
（ドアの開く音）
あ　ヒルダちゃん　お帰り～！
Hilda-chan, welcome back!
あっ！いとこ？超かわいい！
Your cousin? She's so cute!
What's this? A pet?
なに？ペット？
マカオのペットなの～？
It's a Macao pet!
Is this okay? I mean, seriously now...
いろんな意味で大丈夫か？この家。ム～。
What's with this house?
Three Branches of Government!
You're still doing that, Furuichi?
I am not Furuichi, I am Montesquieu.
It seems like you have escaped the danger.
Yeah. But I haven't settled things with Tojo.
I-It's not like I'm doing it
to get Baby Beel back, okay?
On the next Beelzebub: Everyone Assemble!
Although it's not at 8 AM!
Brush your teeth!
You finished your homework?
See you next week!